David Caldwell | Software Engineer

(352) 601-3805 · doubledc92@gmail.com · Asheville, NC · LinkedIn · Portfolio

I am a software engineer with a background in scuba instruction and customer service. I am very customer oriented and feel at ease working as part of a collaborative team. As a web developer I look forward to using my technical skills to build better a better user experience.

SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Trello, Heroku, Surge, Postgres, Python, Redux, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Flask, Git, GitHub, Slack, APIs, SQL **Software:** Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Adobe (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

The Dive Buddy App November 2022

• Utilized React.js components to create a responsive front-end that shows a diver's information.

- Made RESTful API calls to an Express, MongoDB, and Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, and delete (CRUD) operations.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.

More than seven Wonders App

October 2022

- Designed a full stack application with a user interface that displays the seven wonders of the ancient world with reviews.
- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) to build an application in a week with full create, read, update, and delete (CRUD) operations.

Doubles Trouble App October 2022

- Developed a two-player browser game written in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Employed Surge to deploy the web game.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Divers Supply, Service Technician/ Sales Associate

November 2015 – May 2021

- Maintained and managed service operations at a high-volume scuba retail store.
- Overhauled diving equipment for repairs and annual maintenance.
- Facilitated equipment acquisition for customers.

Divers Supply, Scuba Instructor

November 2015 – May 2021

- Instructed over 400 new divers of all ages from 10 to 70.
- Taught small groups of 2 to 8 in the pool and groups up to 30 in open water.
- Assisted new students in completing class registration paperwork.
- Maintained exceptional crowd control and communication above and underwater.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

September 2022 – December 2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Ashworth College

July 2022

AS Computer Information Systems

University of North Florida

September 2017

AA General Studies focused in Graphic Design